<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZHONG on ZHONG</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZHONG on ZHONG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Kevin Xu ZHONG</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR</title>
      <link>/project/crispr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/crispr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Micro-eukaryotic community characterization using deep-amplicons sequencing has been a routine technique in microbiome study in examining health, discovering pathogens, and addressing ecological and evolutionary questions in field of marine biology. A main challenge lies in reducing eukaryotic host signature when using universal 18S rRNA gene markers that capture conservative regions of eukaryotes. Various Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) manipulation in tandem with host-specific blocking primers can be used. However, blocking primers usually target within the universal primers, which could reduce the phylogenetic resolution due to such short fragment, and its application is limited to certain host range. Hence, we report a versatile method that use laboratory-designed and synthesized guiding RNA (gRNA) to guide CRISPR-cas9 to cut specifically the host 18S rDNA amplicon. As a result, the protists and fungal 18S amplicons could be enriched in the sequencing data. This method adds a promising tool to study eukaryotic microbiomes of complex system, offering a broad implication in pathogens diagnosis, symbiotic study, microbiome therapy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applied this method to 10 model-organisms of metazoan and plant, our results showed that up to 99% of host 18S amplicons were digested while not affecting micro-eukaryotic amplicons of protists and fungus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this method, the eukaryotic microbiome has been sucessuflly investiaged for [oyster](), [sealice](),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extending this approach to other metazoan and plant, we are able to design sgRNA for each organism of SILVA database and create a sgRNA database for researchers who want to apply to their own organisms for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This CRISPR work is part of &amp;ldquo;The shellfish gene&amp;rdquo; project funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foundationguide.org/foundations-trust/gordon-betty-moore-foundation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation&lt;/a&gt; during year 2017 - 2021, with aime to investigate the eukaryotic microbiome associated to pacific oysters to understand the causis of high mortality for oyster hatchy in Vancouver area. The CRISPR work lead to two R packages, and two articles publications. Kevin also expend this new method for other organisms by teaching people how to design guiding RNA and he also build a gRNA database for each organism of SILVA database and create a sgRNA database for researchers who want to apply to their own organisms for various purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, let&amp;rsquo;s search, make sgRNA for CRISPR method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search sgRNA for your the host species you want to target (website)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a 18S rRNA sequence of host, search sgRNA to cut (R package)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search sgRNA for your the host species you want to target (R package)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD project</title>
      <link>/project/phd-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/phd-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my PhD project funded by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prefectures-regions.gouv.fr/auvergne-rhone-alpes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Region Rhône-Alpes&lt;/a&gt; during year 2010 - 2013, working in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www6.dijon.inra.fr/thonon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;INRA UMR CARRTEL&lt;/a&gt; at Thonon-les-bains in France under the supervision of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www6.dijon.inra.fr/thonon/Infos-utiles/Le-personnel-de-la-station/CVs-du-personnel/Jacquet-Stephan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Stéphan Jacquet&lt;/a&gt;. During three and half years, I conducted research to investigate and highlight the diversity, distribution, dynamic, and community structure of phytoplankton viruses and their functional roles in three large and deep European peri-alpine lakes: Lakes Annecy, Bourget and Geneva. This PhD work increased and enriched our knowledge in freshwater viral ecology, and was published as 2 book chapters in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.caister.com/vom&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Viruses of Microorganisms&lt;/a&gt; and 11 articles in peer-reviewed journals: Frontier in Microbiology, Applied Environmental Microbiology, Environmental Microbiology, Microbial Ecology, Freshwater Biology, FEMS Microbiology Ecology, Research in Microbiology, Hydrology and Earth System Sciences, etc. With such volume of work, Kevin Xu Zhong&amp;rsquo;s PhD thesis titled “Freshwater dsDNA viral diversity: A special emphasis on viruses infecting phytoplankton (cyanophages and phycodnaviruses) and T4-like myophages in peri-alpine lakes” was selected as the best European PhD Dissertation in Freshwater Sciences during year 2013 - 2014 by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshwatersciences.eu/effs/index.asp?page=NEWS&amp;amp;Id=6&amp;amp;IdItem=193&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;European Federation for Freshwater Sciences&lt;/a&gt;. Kevin obtained in 2014 the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.univ-smb.fr/en/2015/04/14/kevin-zhong-ancien-doctorant-au-laboratoire-carrtel-recoit-le-1er-prix-de-these-de-leffs-european-freshwater-federation-society/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chinese Government Award for Outstanding PhD Students Abroad&lt;/a&gt; by China Scholarship Council, and in 2015 he represented &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.limnologie.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;French Society of Limnology&lt;/a&gt; won the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshwatersciences.eu/effs/index.asp?page=NEWS&amp;amp;Id=6&amp;amp;IdItem=193&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EFFS Award for the best European PhD Dissertation in Freshwater Sciences&lt;/a&gt;. Tremendous thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www6.dijon.inra.fr/thonon/Infos-utiles/Le-personnel-de-la-station/CVs-du-personnel/Jacquet-Stephan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Stéphan&lt;/a&gt;, colleagues from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www6.dijon.inra.fr/thonon/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;INAR UMR CARRTEL&lt;/a&gt;, co-authors, collaborators, members of PhD jury (&lt;a href=&#34;http://biom.obs-banyuls.fr/en/group-4-genophy/group/researchers/yves_desdevises_university_lecturer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yves Desdevises&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sb-roscoff.fr/en/guillou-laure/182&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laure Guillou&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lov.obs-vlfr.fr/fr/presentation_generale/les_equipes_de_recherche/composition_biodiversite_et_biogeochimie.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markus Weinbauer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.i2bc.paris-saclay.fr/spip.php?article386&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Michael DuBow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lienss.univ-larochelle.fr/Montanie-Helene-MCF-HDR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hélène Montanié&lt;/a&gt;), funding sources, families, friends, and people that I may forget their names for their supports during my stay in beautiful France.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribosomes in the sea</title>
      <link>/project/ribosome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ribosome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tula.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tula fundation&lt;/a&gt;, is a new method development that employ extracellular free ribosomes to esimate taxon-specific microbial mortality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimate the cell lysis of microbes based on standing-stock seawater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimate the cell mortatlity rate of microbes based on standing-stock seawater if we know the ribosome turnover rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure the &amp;ldquo;instant&amp;rdquo; cell mortatlity rate of microbes using ribosomes production and decay assay
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project produce xxxx research articles and a R package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to estimate taxon-specific mortality as the result of cell lysis adds an important tool in our quest to explain the distribution and abundance of specific microbial taxa in nature.
The is a method could bridge a gap between viral ecology and microbial ecology to understand &amp;ldquo;whom is lysed?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how many cells were lysed?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;how important the lysis it is? in oceans&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In following link, you can find the [R package]() to estimate the rRNA gene copies per genome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the central role of microbes in biogeochemical cycles in world&amp;rsquo;s ocean, there’s no robust method to measure the taxon-specific mortality. Here, we report a method that employs extracellular free-ribosomes as a proxy to evaluate taxon-specific microbial lysis. The method was validated with laboratory cultures of the marine heterotrophic bacterium Vibrio natriegens strain PWH3a and the photoautotroph Synechococcus sp. strain DC2, with and without grazers or viruses, to identify the origin and fate of the extracellular free-ribosomes. Our results showed both viral lysis and programmed-cell-death (PCD) contribute to free-ribosome production. Ribosomes were not released when cells were grazed, but grazers could consume free-ribosomes. We demonstrated that extracellular free-ribosomes can be used to evaluate microbial mortality caused by viral lysis and PCD. This approach was applied to environmental samples by examining the taxonomic composition and relative abundance of free 16S-ribosomes in seawater samples collected from the Strait of Georgia, British Columbia, Canada. Cell lysis was detected in a wide range and high proportion (up to 34.1%) of prokaryotic taxa. Our results showed high-lysis coupled with low-abundance, suggesting that taxa in lower abundance are subject to higher relative rates of cell lysis, consistent with previous suggestions. The ability to estimate taxon-specific mortality as the result of cell lysis adds an important tool in our quest to explain the distribution and abundance of specific microbial taxa in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st post</title>
      <link>/post/1st-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1st-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is my first post in my webblog&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Jupyter Notebooks with Academic</title>
      <link>/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from IPython.core.display import Image
Image(&#39;https://www.python.org/static/community_logos/python-logo-master-v3-TM-flattened.png&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./academic_0_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;print(&amp;quot;Welcome to Academic!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Welcome to Academic!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-python-and-jupyter&#34;&gt;Install Python and Jupyter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/#download-section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; which includes Python 3 and Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, for advanced users, install Jupyter notebook with &lt;code&gt;pip3 install jupyter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-new-blog-post-as-usual-https-sourcethemes-com-academic-docs-managing-content-create-a-blog-post&#34;&gt;Create a new blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-a-blog-post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;as usual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your Terminal, substituting &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;my-post&lt;/code&gt; with the file path to your Academic website folder and a name for your blog post (without spaces), respectively:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;
hugo new  --kind post post/my-post
cd &amp;lt;MY_WEBSITE_FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/my-post/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-or-upload-a-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Create or upload a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to start Jupyter within your new blog post folder. Then create a new Jupyter notebook (&lt;em&gt;New &amp;gt; Python Notebook&lt;/em&gt;) or upload a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter notebook
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;convert-notebook-to-markdown&#34;&gt;Convert notebook to Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert Untitled.ipynb --to markdown --NbConvertApp.output_files_dir=.

# Copy the contents of Untitled.md and append it to index.md:
cat Untitled.md | tee -a index.md

# Remove the temporary file:
rm Untitled.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-your-post-metadata&#34;&gt;Edit your post metadata&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; in your text editor and edit the title etc. in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/front-matter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt; according to your preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#featured-image&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;featured image&lt;/a&gt;, place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; into your post&amp;rsquo;s folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other tips, such as using math, see the guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Academic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Freshwater Cyanosiphovirus Harboring Integrase</title>
      <link>/publication/cyanosiphovirus_fim_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cyanosiphovirus_fim_2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR method overview</title>
      <link>/tutorial/crispr_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/crispr_overview/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library preparation protocol</title>
      <link>/tutorial/crispr_protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/crispr_protocol/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribosome</title>
      <link>/tutorial/ribosome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/ribosome/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sgRNA oligo making</title>
      <link>/tutorial/crispr_sgrna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/crispr_sgrna/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods and Technologies to Assess Viral Interactions in the Aquatic World</title>
      <link>/publication/book_vom_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/book_vom_method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virus Interactions in the Aquatic World</title>
      <link>/publication/book_vom_interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/book_vom_interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
