<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on ZHONG</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on ZHONG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Kevin Xu ZHONG</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR</title>
      <link>/project/crispr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/crispr/</guid>
      <description>Micro-eukaryotic community characterization using deep-amplicons sequencing has been a routine technique in microbiome study in examining health, discovering pathogens, and addressing ecological and evolutionary questions in field of marine biology. A main challenge lies in reducing eukaryotic host signature when using universal 18S rRNA gene markers that capture conservative regions of eukaryotes. Various Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) manipulation in tandem with host-specific blocking primers can be used. However, blocking primers usually target within the universal primers, which could reduce the phylogenetic resolution due to such short fragment, and its application is limited to certain host range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD project</title>
      <link>/project/phd-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/phd-project/</guid>
      <description>This is my PhD project funded by Region Rhône-Alpes during year 2010 - 2013, working in INRA UMR CARRTEL at Thonon-les-bains in France under the supervision of Dr. Stéphan Jacquet. During three and half years, I conducted research to investigate and highlight the diversity, distribution, dynamic, and community structure of phytoplankton viruses and their functional roles in three large and deep European peri-alpine lakes: Lakes Annecy, Bourget and Geneva. This PhD work increased and enriched our knowledge in freshwater viral ecology, and was published as 2 book chapters in Viruses of Microorganisms and 11 articles in peer-reviewed journals: Frontier in Microbiology, Applied Environmental Microbiology, Environmental Microbiology, Microbial Ecology, Freshwater Biology, FEMS Microbiology Ecology, Research in Microbiology, Hydrology and Earth System Sciences, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribosomes in the sea</title>
      <link>/project/ribosome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ribosome/</guid>
      <description>This project, funded by Tula fundation, is a new method development that employ extracellular free ribosomes to esimate taxon-specific microbial mortality.
 Estimate the cell lysis of microbes based on standing-stock seawater Estimate the cell mortatlity rate of microbes based on standing-stock seawater if we know the ribosome turnover rate Measure the &amp;ldquo;instant&amp;rdquo; cell mortatlity rate of microbes using ribosomes production and decay assay   This project produce xxxx research articles and a R package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>